[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
tricentis tasa Advanced Training as you
all know I already published 66 YouTube
videos covering beginners level
intermediate level and Advan level
Concepts from couple of videos onwards
I've started teaching you the realtime
scenarios where you might encounter
different types of obstacles and how can
we solve those obstacles while
automating your test cases by using
trient
tasom please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos don't forget to like and share
the video thank
you this is our lesson 67 in terms of
overall trient tasar training and this
is our obstacle 25 in terms of real time
scenarios where I'm going to teach you
how can we solve an obstacle where you
need to click on an element which is
hidden in the UI page now let us go and
see in detail what is the obstacle that
we are going to solve for so this is our
obstacle list and our obstacle name is
hidden element which is categorized as
easy so let us go for it
what is the
obstacle who turned off the lights click
the hidden element so here under this
area the black color area there is one
Element you need to click on so that
element is hidden so how can we perform
click operation for the element which is
hidden so for tasa right as long as the
element is visible in
xcam then you can simply solve the
problem so if the element is hidden or
not hidden it doesn't matter for
tasa let us go to tr tasar and solve the
problem so we're going to start working
on the module first as usual I'm going
to scan the object right click on this
obstacles folder select scan and
application so what is the application
so this is my application right select
the application and on
scan so what I would like to do here see
the object is not visible but I have to
guess what object it is how can I guess
I can probably use these elements right
easy hoot on flights so exactly after
this element right or after this object
you can find the hidden
so for that I would like to expand the
filter just simply go towards the right
so here now if you scroll down I should
find easy here right easy this is my
easy let's search for easy see here you
can see easy this is your
simply development right these are all
the developments so here easy after that
you can see there is another div here
you see click this there is a
object click this object which is also a
container div container okay so if you
select this one here you can see this is
uniquely identified if you scroll down
see this has a technical property or
identify the properties technical
property called
ID and which is click this and also it
has a tag as span because this is Spam
this is basically spam tag right and
which is a container so that means this
particular hidden element now I'm able
to identify and this is uniquely
identified by using ID property and span
property and tag
property so now let us rename this
module with the obstacle
name
copy and rename this and save this one
and and close the X scan let us go back
to trient
tasa let us validate if the latest
module is available this is my latest
module double click on this you can see
click this this is my du container so
now let us go to left part which is a
test case section so this is my test
case folder where I'm storing all the
test cases pertaining to different
obstacles so I would like I would
recommend you guys to visit
my previous videos to solve all these
obstacles that we covered till date so
here on this obstacle test case folder
right click on this and create test case
and name this with the same obstacle
name that we captured earlier double
click on this test case now to automate
the scenario simply drag this module
onto test
case and here I can specify click this
particular Hidden Object this is your
hidden object you are not able to see on
the screen right see here you don't see
on the
screen okay but tasa is going to click
on this particular tasa is going to
click on that
particular object simply right click and
then run in scratchbook
see here the object is exactly at this
location clicked and you solve this
automation problem let me try again now
again let's run this again one more time
and see where that object will be
available and where it is going to click
on
see now your object is moved here this
is where the location of the
object so this is how you can solve the
problem where object cannot object may
be hidden but that object you can read
through X scan so if you have any
queries leave your queries in the
comment box I'll try to respond to your
qu is thank you hope you all understand
the concept how can we solve the
obstacle where you need to click on an
element which is hidden in the UI by
using tricentis tasa please do subscribe
to the channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos don't forget to like and
share the video thank you
[Music]